DAMILOLA JERUGBA

(+234) 906 779 1862 - Lagos, Nigeria

hello@damiisdandy.com | linkedin.com/in/damiisdandy | github.com/damiisdandy | damiisdandy.com

Software Engineer (Full Stack)

Software Engineer with 2+ years of full-stack web development experience specializing in ReactJS, NodeJS, Python, Postgresql, and MongoDB. Likes building scalable web infrastructure and making web applications fast. A Technical writer interested in learning and documenting topics on programming languages, algorithms, and developer tooling.

Languages and Skills

Javascript, Python, React, NodeJS, Django, Jest, Cypress, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Docker, CI/CD, Serverless, Git & Agile

Work Experience

OpenSpec: Full Stack Developer | Remote | 04/2022 - 09/2022

- Built full stack application implementing Machine Learning algorithms to aid Product Managers write better Product requirements by generating User Stories, Scenarios, and Edge Cases utilizing OpenAI, React, Prisma & NodeJS.
- Developed multiple End-to-End (E2E) Tests to improve the correctness and health of the entirety of the codebase.
- Prepared software development strategies including test-driven development & constant integration increasing code coverage by 30%.
- Applied performance improvement techniques to global state management which led to a 40% increase in performance and customer satisfaction.

Brimble: Lead Frontend Developer | Remote | 09/2021 - 03/2022

- Implemented technologies such as Progressive Web Application (PWA) to aid website load times and better Search Engine Optimization (SEO) increasing conversion rates by 55%.
- Migrated 3,000+ lines of code in codebase from Vue to React, while implementing view model patterns to improve code maintainability and readability.
- Wrote, Edited & Published 5+ technical articles at <u>DEV.to</u>

<u>Jetron Ticket</u>: Founder & CTO | Lagos, Nigeria | 10/2020 - Present

- Led a team of developers, overseeing daily developments while implementing CI/CD with tools like GitHub Actions, Circle CI, and Digitial Ocean.
- Built full-stack web applications for users to host and discover events around them using technologies such as Python (Django), NodeJS, React, NextJS, monorepos with the creation of design systems.
- Leverage external APIs and effective payment gateways by reducing transaction fees by 20% and for users to discover events around them with Google Maps API, Uber API, and Paystack API.
- Implemented Nodejs as a micro-service to help boost performance by 30% while keeping the codebase maintainable.

Education

BEng in Mechanical Engineering, Graduated in 2022

Landmark University, Kwara Nigeria

GPA: 4.8 / 5.0

College Representative of Engineering and Class Representative

Projects

- <u>Playlist Converter</u> (Python & React) Search/convert playlists from one streaming platform to another with the use of React and FastAPI
- Blockchain visualization (React)
 - A visual representation of Blockchain technology inspired by Anders Brownworth
- <u>damiisdandy/use-pagination</u> (ReactJS & Typescript)
 A personal library with 70+ Github stars to help with pagination in React by building a custom usePagination hook